WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
Shouldn't the hot toast come to me
first, Daisy? Sorry, Mr Carson.
Why is Alfred getting special
treatment? I'm sure he's not.
Why is he getting special treatment?
Why do you think?
Because he's staying here with us.
Oh, this is nice.
Mr Napier and Mr Blake
are coming up in a few days.
He asks if I'm serious about
their staying here.
And are you?
Certainly. They could be useful.
They're writing a report on why
estates like this are going wrong.
But you don't think Downton's
going wrong, do you, My Lady? No.
But I wouldn't mind
having it confirmed.
You seem brighter lately.
Have things sorted
themselves out?
Not quite, but...
It's better.
Yes.
And you've moved back
into the cottage.
I have, My Lady.
Well, you're obviously not going to
tell me what it was about.
But I'm glad if it's resolved.
Nothing for me?
Afraid not.
This is a fine kettle of fish,
I must say.
Your Uncle Harold is in a proper fix.
Why? What's he done this time?
Something to do with oil leases.
Who's Uncle Harold?
Cora's brother.
I always think him rather good at
business, if nothing else.
But it seems he's backed
a very lame horse this time.
Why is he bothering you with it?
I'm not entirely sure. What's that?
It's about the Tamworths. We had Tamworths
at Duneagle. Daddy swears by them.
It's a new thing for us. We haven't
done much with pigs before.
I thought you were convinced.I am.
But... I'm allowed to be nervous.
Intensive farming's a big step.
Half past eight. I must skedaddle.
Penny for your thoughts.
You'd pay twice that
not to know them.
If there was anything I could do...
I know.
It's not your fault, it's mine.
Your husband is a brooder.
And brooders brood.
Then brood about me?
I'm making anchovy sauce
for the fish souffle.
Do you want to watch?
No, you're all right.
His heart's not in it any more.
Oh, I think it is. But when you fall
off a horse, you need a bit of time
to get back in the saddle.
Cousin Cora?
I think you can call me Cora now.
I wouldn't dare with Cousin Robert.
You must dare with me. How can I help?
I...I wanted to tell you that I've
settled the surprise. For his birthday.
Since you won't tell me what it is,
I don't know what to say. Good?
Well, the thing is...
I need Carson to keep the secret.
Do you think he will?
It's only on the day.
And it's only till after dinner.
Mrs Hughes is the one for a secret.
Yes. That's true.
And it'll be she
who has to deal with it.
The second post, Your Ladyship.
Thank you, Spratt. You haven't
taken the netsuke carving from here?
You know the one I mean?
The little ivory fisherman.
I know it, but I've not touched it.
Not to wash it or mend it
or something?
No. And who else has been
in this room in the last day or so?
The maids, of course.
and young Pegg.
He was watering the pot plants.
But Betty was with him.
Watching all the time? Well, no.
She was cleaning.
But... I wouldn't want her blamed.
Oh, I wouldn't blame her.
You know, of course,
the netsuke is very valuable.
That's the risk with little things.
They fit into a pocket easily.
I have a feeling most things would
fit into this particular pocket!
Thank you, Spratt.
My Lady.
We have to get the sums right.
We must speculate to accumulate.
So speaks the American half of you.
Will you really go to America?
Don't worry. I won't go until the
pig business is up and running.
We can give you
masses of introductions.
Grandmamma and Uncle Harold,
for a start.
Lord Grantham got a letter
from him today.
It wasn't good news.
I shouldn't worry. It only means
a yacht's gone aground.
Or a girl's gone back to mother!
That's not what it sounded like.
Right. I'll get the car.
Anything to report?
It's nothing... I'm sure.
But Lady Rose seems to have some
secret she wants Mrs Hughes to keep.
That's more like it.
What secret?
I don't know. It'll be nothing.
Now. Must take this up.
You were dismissed?!
From one minute to the next?
Mr Maley came over. Said I wasn't
needed no more. And that was that.
It's disgraceful!
Is there nothing you can do about it?
No. But I don't understand it.
I had a good touch
with the greenhouses.
I did all the house plants.
I was working well. I know I was.
I'm sure. I'll see if I can
get to the bottom of it.
I'm very grateful, Your Ladyship.
I'm not your la- Oh, never mind.
A band?!
Shh!
No-one must know.
We'll get the carpets rolled up
and everything set during dinner.
So that when His Lordship walks out
of the dining room, there it is.
And we're to hide them until then?
Hide them?
You just have to keep them with you.
His Lordship won't come down here.
So I have to find them food and beds.
How many are there?
Six, I think. But I'll check.
And Her Ladyship knows about it?
Well, not that it's a band, because
it's a surprise for her too.
But she knows that there is a surprise
and that you're helping me with it.
Very well. I'll see what I can do.
Thank you.
I wondered why
Lady Rose was down here.
And I'm afraid
you will continue to wonder.
That's very mysterious, Mrs Hughes.
You know me, Mr Barrow. A woman
of mystery, if ever there was one.
Well, her secret won't affect us.
How can you be so sure?
Now you have got me worried.
I am sorry to hear that, Mr Barrow.
But now you must let me get on.
All I know is this.
I find Pegg in this room
and my paper knife is gone.
He comes into the room again
and a very valuable piece of Japanese
netsuke is missing.
Things. Things. Things!
I don't understand your position.
Are you saying he's justified
in stealing my possessions?
Or do you not believe he took them?
I'm saying you put too much
importance on material objects
and not enough on justice.
Oh, really?
I wonder you don't just set fire to
the abbey and dance round it,
painted with woad and howling!
I might, if it would do any good.
Ah. Well -
I beg your pardon, Your Ladyship.
No. Don't apologise.
I'm glad to have an ally in the room.
This was found
in Betty's cleaning bucket.
It must've rolled in there,
and she's just found it.
Oh.
Thank you, thank you.
I'm very relieved.
Relieved? Or irritated?
If that will be all, My Lady?
Aren't you going to say
you're sorry? Certainly not.
He may not have taken this,
or he may have sneaked it into
the maid's bucket when we weren't looking.
How you hate to be wrong.
I wouldn't know.
I'm not familiar with the sensation.
So you're determined
to dig in your heels.I am sorry.
But whether or not he took this,
he certainly took the knife.
That is all I have to say
on the subject.
Edith.
Whatever's the matter?
Michael's vanished into thin air.
Nobody's heard from him,
no-one can reach him.
I'm sure it's just
a failure of communication.
If anything had happened,
we'd've heard.
Maybe.
I just wish to God
he'd pick up the telephone.
He will.
Come on.
We ought to get changed.
Last post. One for me and er...
one for you, Alfred.
I've got it! It's from The Ritz.
One of the chosen candidates has
dropped out of the course. And I was next.
I was fifth.
See, Jimmy? I was the fifth.
I never said you weren't.
So, they want you, do they?
Yes. I'll have some catching up
to do, but I don't mind that.
Alfred, I'm so pleased for you.
We all are.
That's right. Thank you very much.
When do you go?
As soon as I can. The less I miss,
the less I'm behind.
But it's up to Mr Carson. Oh, I've
no wish to stand in your way, Alfred.
I'm sure I can manage with James
and Mr Barrow. So I can go!
Now? Wait until tomorrow.
We ought to let the family know.
Aren't you going to
congratulate him, Daisy?
Daisy, run and put the kettle on.
You can leave that there.
If you need anything washing,
give it to me tonight.
And me. We'll get you shipshape.
I'm quite nervous now.
What's there to be nervous about?
You're nervous because
you're intelligent, Alfred.
Only stupid people are foolhardy.
I'm ever so sorry, Daisy. Are you?
When you're the one that's driven him away?
How do you make that out?
Because you wanted Jimmy and not him
and that's why he were forced to go.
He knew that.
Come on, girls.
Dry your tears and
let's get on with the dinner.
Ivy, come and beat these eggs.
You're back. I thought
you must've missed the last train.
No. But I only just caught it.
Do you want some dinner?
I ate in the restaurant car.
You weren't very long in London.
There wasn't much to do.
Just sign some papers for a trust
Billy Sheffield set up for his son.
What will that entail?
Mainly, telling the boy to drink
less and be nicer to his mother.
We learned at dinner
that Alfred's leaving.
He's got a place on the Ritz
cookery course after all. Ah.
I'm sorry to cut and run, My Lord.
Don't worry about it.
We're proud of you.
You must return one day
as a famous chef.
My Lord, there's something
I wanted to say.
I've been well treated in this house and I want
you all to know that I'm very grateful.
Thank you, Alfred.
Mr Carson has been a kind...
..and wonderful teacher.
Much more and we shall all
burst into tears.
I'm sorry, My Lord. Come along,
Alfred. Let's get back to work.
How's my birthday dinner coming on?
How do you know about the dinner?
The Coldhursts rang yesterday
and said they'd love to come.
Weren't we all sworn to secrecy?
God! People are so hopeless.
I don't mind. It won't spoil it
if it's not a surprise. Not for me.
There may still be a surprise.
So I should hope!
So, what about tomorrow? I know you'd
enjoy it. What are you going to see?
The Sheikh.
Ooh!
I like that Rudolph Valentino.
Ooh! He makes me shiver all over.
What a very disturbing thought.
Let's us go for a date. We could
leave when we've dressed them
and be back in time
to put them to bed.
Lady Mary wouldn't mind.
Why not? It's been a long time
since we went out to dine.
Too long.
I quite agree.
Will you send a message
to Mr Molesley in the morning?
Why should I?
Because Alfred's going?
So?
Won't you need him now?
I'll need a new footman, yes.
But Mr Molesley has,
as the saying goes,
had his chance and missed it.
You don't mean that. Not
when he agreed to come last time.
Yes, he agreed. Much as
Kaiser Bill agreed to abdicate.
With the greatest possible
reluctance.
But surely -
I'm sorry, Mrs Hughes.
Young Alfred gave thanks tonight
for the courtesy and kindness he has received
here, both from the family and from me.
And that is what I like to see.
Gratitude.
I don't want someone who has to be
dragged into the house by his heels.
Yes, but Mr Molesley has had a lot -
A lot to put up with.
We've all had a lot to put up with,
Mrs Patmore.
And it is not made easier by working
with people who don't want to be here.
It may be worse than you think. They may be
getting ready to lay some people off.
Why would that concern Lady Rose?
Not sure.
But Mrs Hughes seems to think
we could all be affected.
You've got to find out more.
But how?
You'll think of something.
I'll arrange something tomorrow.
Book somewhere special.
If you like.
I know it can't
be the same as it used to be.
I don't deceive myself about that.
But I want to make some
new memories.
Good memories.
So it's not as if
all our happiness was before.
I'm happy... whenever I look at you.
But you're not, are you?
Everything is shadowed.
Every moment we share is shadowed.
You're right.
Let's have... one evening...
when we don't think about it -
we leave it all behind.
Thank you.
Tonight, I'll change before the gong.
I have a committee meeting, and then we're all
dining together in some frightful hotel.
I should leave around six.
What will you wear, My Lady?
Well... I don't want to insult them.
I should look as if I've tried.
Elegant, but sensible. I know.
I'll let you choose. Thank you.
Don't forget to write.
And good luck.
I know you'll get what you want.
Do you? Cos I don't always.
Just remember, you're as good as any
Frenchman. I don't care what they say.
Ah, you're off.
Well... all the luck in the world.
Don't do anything I wouldn't.
There's a bit of leeway!
Where's Daisy?
In the kitchen.
Right. There's a car waiting
to take you. I've just got to...
I'm off!
Goodbye, then.
Daisy, I'm sorry if I've hurt you.
You're good person. You're gonna make
someone very happy one day, but,
it were never gonna be me.
Good luck. I mean it.
You work hard
and you know what you want.
I hope you do well, Alfred.
I think you will.
Alfred? Come along.
We've not a minute to lose.
Thank you, Daisy.
That means a lot to me.
An awful lot.
Ah. Thank you, Mr Carson.
Good morning, ma'am.
I'm afraid you just missed Her
Ladyship. She'll be gone some time.
What a shame. Thank you.
Ooh! Er...
Oh, my goodness.
I feel a bit dizzy.
Might I sit down for a moment?
Of course, ma'am. Please come in.
May I fetch you a glass of water?
No. Thank you, Spratt. I just...
need to sit quietly
for a few minutes.
Certainly, ma'am.
Please ring if you need anything.
Eureka!
You've been kind.
But I'm feeling much better.
So... I'll be on my way.
Oh.
Would you give this to Lady Grantham
on her return?
I found it down the side
of the chair I was sitting in.
She will be pleased.
She was very upset at its loss.
I hope she'll be pleased.
I'm not certain that she will.
But I hope so.
Mr Molesley.
What can I do for you?
I was at the station this morning.
We're... we're renewing
the gravel out front.
And erm... I ran into young Alfred.
He's off on his way to London.
Yes.
So er... as he is going after all,
I thought...
..I'll look in... to confirm my
willingness to... return to Downton.
Mr Molesley. I'm glad you are,
as you put it, willing.
But I cannot feel
the word expresses... the kind of...
enthusiasm I am looking for
in a new footman.
What?
When we last discussed it,
you made it quite clear that you didn't wish
to plunge down the ladder of preferment.
I was willing to.
As you keep saying.
But I don't want to humiliate you.
You feel you're meant for
better things.
And I won't contradict you.
Unfortunately,
we have no higher place to offer
in this house.
I know. But I said...
And you have your pride...
and I respect you for it.
Good day, Mr Molesley.
Mrs Crawley and Dr Clarkson,
Your Ladyship.
Oh. To what do I owe this treat?
Lady Grantham,
you've already changed for dinner.
We'll erm...
we'll come back tomorrow.
No. My curiosity...
would not brook such a delay.
Did Spratt give you the paper knife?
Yes. Then it's quite clear
that Pegg did not steal it.
Or are you going to argue now that
he sneaked it back in here when
he realised what trouble he was in?
Well...
It's a thought.
But a despicable one.
What can I say to persuade you
out of your injustice and stubbornness?
Can't you see the damage you do?
Now...
Hold your horses, Mrs Crawley.
Lady Grantham has a right of reply.
Oh, thank you, Dr Clarkson. Now, if you
will put up your cudgels for a moment...
Oh, Spratt. Has the young gardener
Pegg brought in the vegetables yet?
What?
He's in the kitchen now, My Lady.
Please ask him to step in here.
Into the drawing room, Your Ladyship?
Well, ask him to remove his boots,
if that will soothe your nerves.
I don't understand. No.
If you wish to understand things,
you must come out from behind
your prejudice and listen.
Your Ladyship? Yes. Could you
give an account to Mrs Crawley
of what transpired between us
this afternoon?
I'm... sorry, My Lady?
Tell her what I said to you.
Her Ladyship sent for me. So I came.
She said she'd been mistaken
in saying that I were a thief,
which she knew now to be untrue.
She gave me my job back.
Said she was sorry and...
asked if I could forgive her.
Which you have.
I certainly have, Doctor.
Thank you. You may go.
Out. Come on.
Well?
Well... I'd say that was game,
set and match to Lady Grantham.
You're dining at The Netherby?
I know. It's quite something,
isn't it, My Lady?
I don't think we've eaten in a hotel
since before we were married.
You don't mind, do you?
Not at all. And don't rush back.
It won't kill me
to get myself to bed.
I'll be back, don't you worry.
Did I tell you that Mr Napier and
Mr Blake will be here in time for dinner
on his Lordship's birthday?
Rather a baptism of fire.
How long are they going to stay?
I'm not sure.
It's open-ended.
Which Granny would never approve of.
Bates?
I don't seem to have it.
Could you look again? Because
we definitely made a reservation.
Maybe you each thought
the other had done it.
I made the booking.
I'm afraid we're very full tonight.
The Countess of Grantham
has a large party with her.
Lady Grantham's here?
Among our patrons
are some of the greatest names
in Yorkshire society.
And the countess is among them.
Yes. We know her.
Huh! Oh.
These people claim to know you,
Your Ladyship.
Well, we didn't...
I know them both very well indeed.
You're dining here, Anna? We were. But
there seems to be a mix-up with the table.
Well, I'm sure it can be sorted out.
In a jiffy, My Lady. In a jiffy.
If you would like to wait
one moment.
That seems to have made
a difference. Thank God he's a snob.
My Lady, I promise you - I'm sure not.
But don't let's spoil the effect now.
To be honest,
I wish I could join you.
But I'd better get back.
Well, if you'd like to follow me...
And er... please excuse
the little hiccup earlier.
It will be the last.
Ah. Yes.
I do apologise, My Lady.
But this came in the evening post
and it appears
to have been overlooked.
Not to worry.
[Pregnancy confirmation letter]
- Is anything the matter?
- No. Not at all.
Why, Mr Molesley.
How can we help you?
I was... wondering...
..if by any chance er...
Mr Carson had changed his mind.
I'm afraid not.
I'd've thought
he'd value my... caution.
My wanting to...
weigh up the pros and cons
before rushing in.
So, is this it, then?
Do I just go back to
mending the roads?
Oh, don't give up so easily.
Now. Let me get some more hot water.
Look. There's a seat over there.
Let's sit down.
We're not in a hurry.
If you say so.
Such a lovely night.
Look at that moon.
It's as bright as a light bulb.
So, what do you make of
this Valentino chappy, then?
Is he your type?
He is not. I think he's slithery.
If I were Agnes, I'd've gone straight back
to London as quick as I could find a boat.
So, you don't like romance?
Well... I wouldn't say that.
Get off, will you?! Get off me!
I've been good to you, Ivy.
I've taken you to the theatre, and to the cinema. I've
never been that nice to any girl before.
Am I supposed to feel lucky?
It's dishonest to take from a bloke
without giving him in return.
I don't think it's playing the game.
Well, I'm not playing YOUR game!
And you'd better
get used to that idea.
Here's to us.
Sorry.
I was a fool to think
we could leave it behind.
Don't be sorry. I'm sorry.
But you see, every time I remember
what you've been through...
I want to murder.
But I'm not a victim.
That's not who I am.
The worst part is,
you see me as a victim.
No, my darling. I see you as
a woman I should've protected.
I'm the failure here, not you.
Can I interrupt?
I wondered if you
want a lift home. Stark's here.
That seems such an imposition.
Not at all. And it should mean you
get a table here for the rest of your life.
Can we have our coats, please?
The three of us?
It would be my pleasure.
This is very kind, My Lady.
Have you had a good evening?
Yes.
Yes, very good, thank you.
Well, don't sound so hesitant, or
the maitre d' will kill himself!
No, we've had a lovely time.
He didn't hurt you?
No.
But he asked for things no man
should want before they're married.
Yes. I think we're a bit more clear
about that than they are.
I suppose he's been sweet-talking me
so he could have his way.
I thought he was so nice. How many women
have said that since the Norman Conquest?
Alfred would never have done such
a thing. He had too much respect.
Don't start.
What do you mean?
You break Alfred's heart, so now he's alone
in a city that terrifies him.
You break my heart
by driving him away.
I don't care about
your good opinion of Alfred.
If you'd discovered it earlier,
you'd've spared us a lot of grief.
What was all that about?
Oh, I'd say it was about the fact
that you've had it coming.
It was nice of you to
give them a lift. I was glad to.
But...
I may be mistaken, but I'm afraid
things have gone wrong between those two.
That's sad to hear. It's not just
a case of a marriage gone sour.
Anna's been hurt somehow. And Bates
feels he should've protected her.
I don't want any of that
to leave this room, Baxter.
Course not, My Lady.
Edith? My most darling girl.
What's the matter?
But I'm not your most darling girl,
am I?
I love my children equally.
I don't know why people say that
when it's almost never true.
Look, if this is about Michael Gregson, do you
want me to get involved? Send someone over?
No.
His office has already done that.
There's a detective in Munich now,
working with the German Police.
Then you just have to be patient.
I want to know what's happened.
If he's... trapped somewhere or...
falsely imprisoned.
Or even dead.
I mean it.
If the worst's happened,
I want to know.
It's just so impossible to plan
in this... fog.
Well, I'm sure he's not dead.
No, you aren't.
Because none of us can be.
But how was she hurt?
What happened to her?
I'm just telling you what
Her Ladyship told Lady Mary.
I don't know anything else.
Then keep your ears open.
I always do.
What's the matter?
I don't really like telling tales.
You knew the conditions
when you came here.
I did.
So, what's changed?
She's polite, she's...
considerate.
I don't feel she's deserved it.
Now, listen.
What you have to decide
is where your first loyalties are.
With her... or with me.
All right.
Have it your own way.
Oh, I intend to.
Thank you.
It's so kind of you all to have us.
Isn't it, Charles?
It is.
We're anxious to do our bit.
What do you mean by that?
Well, you're here to advise
the landowners on how to get through
this crisis, aren't you?
To save the estates that need saving.
I'm afraid Evelyn may have given you
the wrong impression.
In what way?
The government is aware
that great estates are being sold
in large numbers.
Precisely. North Yorkshire has a lot
of these estates, big and small.
And many are in difficulty. We will have
every variety of problem to study.
And you're here to help.
Not quite.
We're here to analyse the situation
and ask whether our society
is shifting fundamentally.
Will it affect food production,
and so on?
So... you don't care about the owners,
just about food supply.
If that's how you want to put it...
And doesn't that seem mean-spirited?
Mr Lloyd George is more concerned
with feeding the population
than rescuing the aristocracy.
I don't find that mean-spirited.
You may find us disappointing guests
if you want us to stay up till
two in the morning being witty.
Don't worry. I don't expect
Mr Blake to be witty!
How long will you be here? Until the job is
done and we can write a report.
If you'll have us.
You must be sure to get rid of us
when we become a nuisance.
The gong is rung at seven and we
meet in the drawing room at eight.
You know it's Robert's birthday?
So you must try to be witty tonight,
Mr Blake.
After that,
we'll lower our expectations.
The girls will show you up.
Hello, Mr Molesley. There's a chair
here. No, I'm not here to eat.
Why have you come, then?
Mrs Hughes sent for me.
She said you had a big party tonight
and it'd be useful to Mrs Patmore
if I serve the servants tea.
What?
Mrs Patmore has a lot to do.
Mr Molesley said he would help.
To serve the servants tea?
He's not proud, Mr Carson.
He wants to be useful
where he can be.
Oh, all right. I give in!
I cannot fight a war on every front.
Mr Carson?
Look out a livery.
You can start tonight,
move in tomorrow.
Thank you, Mr Carson. Very much.
And don't forget the gloves.
Lady Rose! Can I help? Oh, please.
Don't let me disturb you.
But I wanted to make a speech.
Mrs Hughes may have told you -
I haven't yet.
Well, we should tell them now.
As a treat for His Lordship,
a London band is coming to play
after dinner.
A London band. That's the berries.
From a nightclub called The Lotus.
A nightclub, My Lady? Really?
But it must be a complete surprise.
No-one knows anything.
And they mustn't. That is,
Her Ladyship knows something's going
to happen, but even she doesn't know what.
And you think she'll be pleased.
She'll be thrilled.
We'll look after your secret.
So, until then, if you can just
make them comfortable.
I know musicians are outside
your daily round.
Don't worry about that, My Lady.
We can take it in our stride.
We may be Yorkshiremen, but we do
know a little of life in the city.
Hello? Uh... is anyone there?
I think this is where
we're supposed to be.
Welcome to Downton.
I thought I'd come up early...
and spend some time with George.
I told Nanny I'd feed him.
But now you can do it.
He'd like that.
Oh, I doubt it.
He probably thinks, who's this
funny old lady? But never mind.
By the way...
I thought I'd be Grandmamma.
And then Cora can be Granny.
And what about Sybbie?
What should she call you?
Well, Aunt Isobel, I think. I'm not
quite a real aunt, but I nearly am.
Did I read that your friend
Lord Gillingham is engaged?
Yes. To Miss Lane Fox.
I hope you don't mind. I should so
hate for you to be unhappy.
I'm not unhappy.
I'm just... not quite ready
to be happy.
When I got engaged, I was so
in love with Reginald I felt sick.
I was sick with love.
Literally.
It seems so odd to think about it
now. It really does.
It was the same for me.
As if I'd gone mad, or been
hypnotised, or something. For days.
Weeks.
All I could think about was her.
And me.
I was standing outside
in the snow...
and I didn't have a coat.
But I wasn't cold...
because all I kept thinking was...
He's going to propose.
Well.
Aren't we the lucky ones?
Oh! Look who's here!
Hello, Sybbie.
Hello.
Have you never thought of
visiting Africa?
And why should I go to Africa,
Mr Carson?
I'm no more African than you are.
Well... not much more.
My people came over in the 1790s.
We won't go into why or how.
Oh, no. Better left unsaid.
Mr Ross.
You've uncovered something about the
past that Mr Carson doesn't approve of.
Well done!
Not so fast, Mrs Hughes. We led the
world in the fight against slavery.
Remember Lord Henley's judgment
of 1763?
'If a man sets foot
on English soil...
then he is free.'
Don't undo Mr Ross's good work.
Ivy. When I said that I could -
Oh, goodness. Is that the time?
I'm first down. I just want to check
everything's on track.
I gave them something to eat, as they'll be
playing during the servants' dinner.
Yes, that was very kind.
Wait until Carson has
everyone in their seat
before you start setting up.
I will.
Well...
..she's quite a character.
Lady Rose?
That's one word for her!
But I can't help feeling sorry
for the poor pigs.
Do you eat bacon?
Yes.
Sausages?
Then you are a sentimentalist
who cannot face the truth.
I'm not often called sentimental.
Your friend seems to be putting
Mary through her paces.
I'm afraid, Charles will take on
anyone with a sense of entitlement.
You mean, Mary feels entitled to take
charge? She's welcome to take charge of me.
Molesley. Glad to be back?
Surprised, more like, My Lady.
But I suppose I'll be called...
Joseph now.
I...I don't think I can manage that.
Nor can I.
Carson, you don't mind if we go on calling Molesley
Molesley, do you? Of course not, My Lord.
Why do you want to emigrate?
Because I realised
I'd never fit in at Downton.
They're very fond of you here.
I think they are.
And I'm fond of them.
I love them, really.
Though, it surprises me to say it.
But I'm not one of them.
And I cannot make a life here.
Why not?
Would there be another earl's daughter
who'd be keen to take me on, do you think?
Oh, I don't know.
It would depend on her.
No. She wouldn't.
There aren't many...
as free as my Sybil.
Well, I agree with that.
So... should I bring a nice
Irish working girl to live here?
Would that make everyone comfy?
Isobel really appears to be
coming out of the mist.
I'm so pleased.
Well, don't be too pleased.
Part of her recovery
is going back into battle.
If she's fighting for her causes
again, that seems a good sign.
A sign of what?
That we should close the shutters
and bar the door?
She likes to fight
for what she believes in.
Oh, no. It's not a matter of
what she likes. It is her fuel.
Some people run on... greed...
..lust, even love.
She runs on indignation!
I'm catching the ladies' eye.
Oh, no.
Rose?
No. We're not splitting tonight.
We're all going out together.
What on earth is she talking about?
What?
Quick - play!
And a one, two, three.
Happy birthday, Cousin Robert!
I say!
♪ I'm just wild about Harry ♪
♪ And Harry's wild about me ♪
♪ The heavenly blisses of his kisses ♪
♪ Fill me with ecstasy ♪
♪ He's sweet, just like chocolate candy ♪
♪ And just like honey from bees... ♪
Who is this singer?
And how did he get here?
Isn't it... rather odd?
No, I think it's fun.
♪ He's just wild about me... ♪
But, Granny, is it really... suitable
that Rose has brought this man here?
Oh, my dear, we country-dwellers
must beware of being provincial.
Try and let your time in London
rub off on you a little, hm?
I'd love to know which estates
you're going to examine.
I'm sure you would.
You mustn't be too discreet.
After a while, it gets a little dull.
You seem to have brought
a traitor into our midst.
Not a traitor.
An enemy, then.
He's obviously not on our side.
It is a bit wild...
jazz at Downton Abbey.
I think it's lovely.
You see, Tom...
things can happen at Downton
that no-one imagined
even a few years ago.
Take heart from that.
Before you throw in the towel.
Is this your first experience
of jazz, Lady Grantham?
Oh, is that what it is?
Do you think any of them know
what the others are playing?
Hm?
♪ He's just wild about me ♪
Did you ask me to come down?
I did.
We've made some sandwiches for you
and the others,
as I doubt you'll be off duty
before midnight.
We'll set a little table inside the green
baize door. They sound good from down here.
If you like that sort of thing.
I thought Mr Ross was very nice.
So did I, strange to relate.
Though, it's still an odd sort of
thing to be happening at Downton.
Makes you want to jig about,
dun't it? Certainly not!
I think...
I think we've done enough now.
You know - to show that we're
good sports. Of course, of course.
I do think it was a brilliant idea.
But it must be costing Rose
a fortune.
Shall we chip in?
Or pay it. Get the bandleader
to send me the bill.
I'll go down at the end of the night
and catch him before he leaves.
I'm afraid I don't
share your enthusiasm for her.
Why not? She's the type
who demands all this as a right.
But she wants it on a plate.
She won' work for it
and she won't fight for it.
And that type
doesn't deserve to survive.
I don't want to make trouble...
but she feels
much the same about you.
Oh, Edith!
I wish you'd tell me what's wrong.
How do you know something's wrong?
Because I'm your mother.
Is it Michael? Is there any news?
Not really.
He went to Munich a few weeks ago.
That's all they know.
Well, of course you're worried.
Well, it's not often that a birthday
surprise really is a surprise.
I just hope we haven't
shocked the servants too much.
Carson was ready to faint.
Although, amazingly,
he told me that the bandleader...
'..was a very decent fellow,
My Lord.'
So perhaps we'll make a modern of
him after all.I doubt it.
Oh. And there's no news on Mr Gregson.
He's still missing.
Edith told me.
But I'm sure he'll be fine.
By the way. Did you ever read
that letter from Harold? I did.
And I've had one from Mother.
I didn't wanna bother you.
But I think he's in a deep hole.
Have you ever met this Senator Fall?
Not that I remember.
I suppose he may be innocent.
Nothing's been proved.
The one thing that has been proved
is that Harold was a fool to get involved.
Don't get riled about it now.
Come to bed and dream of ragtime.
Is anyone still awake?
Mary?
What are you doing down here?
I was looking for Mr Ross.
Mr Ross, I wanted to thank you
for a marvellous evening.
And also to ask you if you would be kind
enough to send the bill to His Lordship.
But that's not necessary.
He wants to.
He says... your present
was arranging the whole thing.
Of course.
And now it's my turn to thank you.
I've been so well looked after here.
I'm glad to hear it.
Well... goodnight.
His Lordship is going to America?
'Robert must be there.' Why?
My being there won't make any difference.
I'm feeling rather ill. I wanted him
away before I... keel over.
How can two brainless dullards like
us ever hope to entertain Mr Blake?
Mary!
That sounded a little rude.
How long have you been like this?
I really don't feel well at all.
Darling, please tell me what's the matter.
You've seemed so... preoccupied lately.
I think this is the right place.
Well, it is Mr Gillingham!
I suppose you could
to shake us up again.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.